David Stewart

Professional Summary

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Collaborative team member with excellent technical abilities.

Quality-oriented professional with 10 years of experience an a proven knowledge of computer integrated manufacturing, work methods analysis, and research development practices. With an eye for quality.

Work History

Allied Automation - PROGRAMMER AND MACHINIST

Apex, NC

03/2020 - 06/2022

- Created complex multiple staged programs for high precision machining
- Maintained tight tolerances with design specifications.
- Used CNC and manual equipment to perform both initial and final machining.
- Studied work instruction, sketches, drawings, blueprints and manuals to determine dimensions and tolerances accurately.
- Obtained blueprints and materials from suppliers and engineers.
- Reduced run times and costs by implementing innovative and best practices. Reducing some programs runtimes by more than 50%.
- Manually set up machinery, vertical mills and grinders.

Griffin Motion - PROGRAMMER AND MACHINIST

Apex, NC

06/2018 - 03/2020

- Measure, examine, or test completed units to check for defects and ensure conformance to specifications, using precision instruments, such as micrometers.
- Study sample parts, blueprints, drawings, and engineering information to determine methods and sequences of operations needed to manufacture products, and determine product dimensions and tolerances.

- ✓ davidstew87@gmail.com
- (919) 452-1260
- **Q** Durham, NC 27713

Website, Portfolio, Profiles

- https://dav3ster.github.io/The-Real-Deal/
- https://github.com/Dav3ster
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidstewart-8b046725a/

Skills

- JavaScript Programming
- Express Js
- Back-End and Database Skills
- Front-End Skills: HTML, CSS, React
- Version Control Systems: Git, GitHub
- Responsive Web Design
- Schematics Reading
- Design Specifications
- CAD Utilization

Education

03/2023

UNC Chapel Hill

Chapel Hill, NC

Certificate: Full Stack Web Development Recently completed UNC Chapel Hill's full stack web development boot-camp. Proficient in frontend technologies such as

- Confer with engineering, supervisory, or manufacturing personnel to exchange technical information.
- Program CNC vertical mills using conversational (CAPS) software and HSM Express for solid works.
- Design fixtures, tooling, or experimental parts to meet special engineering needs.
- Evaluate experimental procedures, and recommend changes or modifications for improved efficiency and adaptability to setup and production.

CA Foy Machine Co - CNC MACHINIST AND SHIFT MANAGER

Kings Mountain, NC

04/2013 - 06/2018

- Calculate dimensions and tolerances using knowledge of mathematics and instruments such as micrometers and Vernier calipers.
- Align and secure holding fixtures, cutting tools, attachments, accessories, or materials onto machines.
- Set up, adjust, and operate all basic machine tools and many specialized or advanced variation tools to perform precision machining operations.
- Oversee activities directly related to making products or providing services.
- Manage staff, preparing work schedules and assigning specific duties.
- Trained and mentored new employees to maximize team performance.
- Maximized tooling speeds and feeds for best performance.

HTML, CSS, React. Along with backend technologies such as Mongo, Express, Node, GraphQL, Apollo, SQL, and JavaScript. Utilizing these tools I've learned to build intuitive responsive web and mobile applications.